ligatus.de 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy | Ligatus

##  Privacy Policy 

### Privacy policy of the Ligatus Group in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

This Privacy Policy applies to the web services and websites of Ligatus GmbH, Christophstraße 19, 50670 Cologne, Germany, represented by Liesbeth Mack-de Boer, Klaus Ludemann and Arne Wolter, - hereinafter referred to as "Ligatus" - and also to the microsites operated by Ligatus for its customers and, if applicable, further advertising materials which are maintained by Ligatus for its customers, in particular also advertising materials for the delivery of personalised and behaviour-based advertising on the Internet (see section IV).

**This Privacy Policy is always to be regarded as part of the respective web presence which directly refers to this site (e.g. under “Privacy” or “Privacy Policy”).**

As a controller in accordance with the the General Data Protection Regulation, Ligatus takes the protection of your personal data very seriously. We would like to inform you about when we collect what data and how we use it. We have implemented extensive technical and organisational measures (Art. 32 GDPR) to ensure compliance and adherence with applicable provisions on data protection and data security and as well contracted third party providers. Please note that amendments to this Privacy Policy may be required due to the ongoing development of our websites and the implementation of new technologies to improve our web services. We therefore recommend frequently referring back to this Privacy Policy and reading through the current up-to-date version, which is always available online under http://www.ligatus.com/en/privacy-policy.

### I. What is personal information?

According to Art.4 No. 1 GDPR, personal data is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, therefore can be used to obtain personal or factual details about the data subject (such as name, address, telephone number, date of birth or e-mail address). Information that cannot (directly or indirectly) be associated with a natural person (or only with disproportionate effort), for example anonymous information, is not personal information.

### II. What information do we collect and process?

You can use a portion of our online content without providing personal information.

_a) Contact forms_

If you however decide to request further information via the contact forms provided on our websites or the microsites operated on behalf of our customers, we will ask for your name and further personal information in order to handle your personal request or to provide the services you requested from us or our customers. Please note that the exact scope of the collected information varies depending on the relevant campaign and services offered by the relevant customer, and will be specified in the contact form of each campaign (all mandatory fields are marked with *). You can freely decide whether or not you want to provide the requested information. However, without this information, we are unable to make the desired services available to you. We will always make sure that you know exactly what data you are sending for what purpose and what happens with it - according to and covered by your express consent.

_b) Ligatus newsletter_

As part of our web services, we offer a regular subscription to our Ligatus newsletter. When requested, the newsletter provides you with free, up-to-date information on our services and the Ligatus blog. To register to our Ligatus newsletter service, we need your first and last name, your gender, and the e-mail address at which you wish to receive the newsletter. If you wish to subscribe to the Ligatus newsletter, we ask that you provide us with the following declaration of consent:

> I would like to regularly receive the Ligatus newsletter, and agree that my e-mail address, my first and last name, and my gender, as well as any data voluntarily provided, be used for this purpose. I can revoke this declaration of consent at any time by using the “Opt-Out function” in the respective Ligatus Newsletter or via e-mail notice to info@ligatus.com, as well as by writing to Ligatus GmbH, Christophstraße 19, 50670 Köln, Germany, such revocation to take effect for the future. No additional fees beyond the normal transmission fees of my e-mail or Internet provider shall apply. In the event that my consent is revoked, I shall not, or shall no longer, be able to receive the Ligatus newsletter. I have read and accept the current privacy policy.

_c) “Double opt-in procedure”_

In order to acquire your consent when ordering the Ligatus newsletter, we use the “double opt-in procedure”. This means that we will only send you the Ligatus newsletter once you have confirmed your registration via a confirmation e-mail sent to you for this purpose, by clicking on the link contained therein. By doing this, we wish to ensure that only you yourself as the owner of the e-mail address given are able to make use of our services.

### III. How does Ligatus use your personal information

Personal information is also requested by us for billing and promotional purposes and processed by us or by our partners and customers (e.g. when ordering information or premiums). The usage of your personal information varies depending on the relevant campaign and customer. You will be informed thoroughly about any usage of your personal information on the relevant website or within the relevant campaign.

Your personal information, that was transmitted in that way, is not used for purposes that you did not explicitly agree to when requesting our services or within the scope of the relevant campaign. Without your consent, your information will not be used e.g. for marketing purposes. You will only receive advertising if you have given your explicit consent. You can revoke your consent any time by using [our contact form](http://www.ligatus.com/#footer) on this website or sending an email to [info@ligatus.com](mailto:info@ligatus.com) or your Ligatus contact person. However, in this case Ligatus may no longer be able to provide the offered services.

In addition to personal information collected about you via our contact forms or microsites operated on behalf of our customers or business partners, which will strictly be used to provide the relevant services to you, our web servers log general information on the usage of our websites (such as: date and time, visited websites - e.g. when each page was viewed or which page was visited most frequently).

Such log data is processed for system security reasons (to prevent abuse of our web services), to improve our websites and web services and as well for statistical purposes (number of users and page views). However, we do not analyse personal information.

### IV. Delivery of personalised or behaviour-based advertising (behavioral targeting)

In certain cases, we showcase advertising to you on the websites of our partners and for our customers, which are automatically selected on the basis of your surfing behaviour, in order to optimise the quality of the advertising notices for you (so-called "personalised" or "behaviour-based" advertising delivery and "behavioral targeting". The objective of this system is to only demonstrate to you those commercials which may correspond to your interests. Advertising notices which are unlikely to be of interest to you or which are irrelevant will not be shown to you by the activated behavioral targeting system of Ligatus and will be disabled.

In such a case, this section IV. of the data protection declaration applies as part of the respective web-based services of our partners or customers, from which (for example under "data protection" or "data protection declaration" direct reference was made or a link was created. We wish to disclose to you in a transparent manner how the behavioral targeting works, which data is gathered in the process, how this data is used and for what purpose and how you can object to the behavioral targeting function at any time and block it.

As a German/European company, the protection of your data is a priority for Ligatus, also in the course of the delivery of behaviour-based advertising and Ligatus only uses anonymised data to improve advert quality. Therefore, an identification of your person is not possible either for Ligatus or the respective operator of the website of our partners and customers which you are visiting. You can yourself decide at any time whether you would like to continue seeing personalised banner from Ligatus.

**Important:** User data is processed exclusively in European computer centres.

Ligatus has voluntarily obliged itself to comply with the [OBA framework of the EDAA / AB Europe](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/2012-06-08_iab_europe_oba_framework.pdf) and provides regular proof of this within the framework of its annual certification in accordance with these parameters.

_a) How does behavioral targeting work in individual cases?_

When visiting the website of one of our partners or customers, a cookie file is stored on your computer. Cookies are small text files which are deposited by your web browser in a folder on your computer which is designated for this purposes and which contains a single character string as a means of identification. (The cookie does not store your IP address.) The same character string is also saved on our servers. The next time you visit one of our partners' websites, only the character string is read which identifies the Internet browser you are using. This allows us, for example, to identify which page you have accessed for our partner and which advert you have been shown, without this being linked to your identity. Furthermore, all of the cookies created by us are given an expiry data and automatically expire after no more than 13 months. Without a valid cookie file, the character strong saved on our servers is no longer to be assigned for us.

**Important:** Using cookies we cannot ever collect any other personal data. For example, when you enter an email address or delivery address, or any other personal data, we cannot see your input and cannot therefore process or store it. We do not know your name, address or workplace, nor do we know your gender, age, email address or any other personally identifiable information about you. Even the IP address of your computer is not stored! You can view the data stored in the cookie on your computer. Please refer to your web browser’s help directory or your web browser’s FAQ to learn how cookies are stored and how to read their content. The information contained within the cookie is the exact data that we can see Cookie technology does not allow viruses, trojans or other harmful programs to be placed on your computer.

A full list of the cookies used by Ligatus and their individual functions can be downloaded [here](http://i.ligatus.com/privacytext/de/Ligatus_Cookie_Documentation.pdf) at any time. Should you not agree to the saving of cookies on our part, you can examine your cookie status at the very top of this page at any time, and also deactivate the saving of behavioral targeting cookies by us. Therefore you can object to the personalised adverts from Ligatus at any time.

_b) How can I check whether personalised advertising from Ligatus is enabled on my computer?_

[Here](http://www.ligatus.com/en/privacy-policy#cookie_status) you can check whether personalised advertising from Ligatus is enabled (“Opt-In”) or disabled (“Opt-Out”) in your computer.

_c) How can I disable personalised advertising from Ligatus banners?_

If you do not agree to the storing of cookies by us, you can check your cookie status at any time [here](http://www.ligatus.com/en/privacy-policy#cookie_status) and disable the storage of retargeting cookies by us and therefore decline personalised adverts from Ligatus.

This means that in future you will receive random advertising that is not targeted to your interests. Please note that the "opt-out" and "opt-in" functions offered are, for technical reasons, also controlled via cookies.This means that deleting all cookies on your computer means that you will have to opt-out again.

It is also the case that the deletion of all cookies on your computer does not lead to no personalised advertising being notified to you on a permanent basis. Therefore, you must use the following link to the "opt out" function which is provided, should you not wish for behaviour-based advertising to be delivered to your computer or your end devices. At the following address http://www.ligatus.com/en/privacy-policy#cookie_status you can change your current cookie status at any time.

Finally, please note that we are continuously expanding our range of products. As this will technically involve a new system, the introduction of a new opt-out may be necessary, even if you have already opted prior to its introduction.

_d) Can other forms of personalised advertising be disabled in addition to Ligatus?_

The options described in this section refer only to the personalised adverts offered by Ligatus. If you wish to disable personalised advertising from other providers, you can do this via their respective websites.

There is an option to change your settings collectively for various providers under preference management on “Your Online Choices”:http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/.

### V. Anonymous data/use of cookies

We also use cookies on the Ligatus websites. Cookies are small text files, stored by your web browser in a dedicated directory on your computer or mobile device. Cookies are solely used to identify your web browser in an anonymous manner to optimise the display of targeted advertising messages on our websites or the websites of our partners (see in particular the following section 6 concerning the use of Google Analytics and Google Remarketing).

Our cookie files only contain automatically generated ID numbers and a time stamp. We neither know your name, the place you live or work, nor do we know your gender, your age, your e-mail address or any other similar information about you. The IP address of your device will also not be stored. You can view the data stored in the cookie on your computer. Please refer to your web browser’s help directory to learn how cookies are managed. The information contained within the cookie is the exact data that we can see Cookie technology does not allow viruses, trojans or other malware to be placed on your computer.

You can also use our websites without the use of cookies enabled. Most browsers accept cookies automatically. You can disable the storage of cookies or set your browser to notify you before accepting the storage of cookies. Please note that users who do not accept the storage of cookies may not be able to access certain functionality of our websites, or can only use our websites with considerable difficulty.

Further information and a full list of the cookies which are used by Ligatus on its own websites or on those of customers or partners, as well as their individual functions, can be downloaded [here](http://i.ligatus.com/privacytext/de/Ligatus_Cookie_Documentation.pdf) at any time. In addition, you can generally prevent the storing of cookies by adjusting your browser settings accordingly.

### VI. Usage of Google Analytics and Google Remarketing

_a) The Ligatus websites use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA („Google“). Google Analytics uses cookies, which are text files placed on your computer or your mobile device, to help the website analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted and stored by Google on servers in the United States._

Please note, that the application of Google Analytics within our web services has been enhanced with the code „gat._anonymizeIp();“ to enable the anonymous logging of IP addresses (so-called “IP-masking”). Prior to the transmission, your IP address will be truncated by Google within the member states of the European Union or other parties to the accord on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address sent to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data collected or held by Google.

Google uses this information on our behalf to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide the website operator with more services related to the website and internet use. Google may also transmit the information to third parties when required by law or when third parties process the information on behalf of Google.

You can disable the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note, that if you do so, you may not be able to use the full functionalities of this website.

You can also disable the collection of the information generated by the cookie concerning your use of the websites and the processing of these data by Google, by installing the browser plug-in available for download via the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

As an alternative to the above mentioned browser plug-in or when using mobile devices, you can disable the collection of the information generated by the cookie by clicking the following link: Disable Google Analytics.

An opt-out cookie will be then stored that disables the collection of your information for future visits of our websites.

Further information is available here: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en (general informationen on Google Analytics and privacy).

_b) We also allow Google to place cookies on our websites for the purpose of use-based online advertising_

The cookie stored on your computer by Google allows the anonymised recognition of your browser by Google and gathers information about your activities on the websites you visit (e.g. web surfing behaviour, subpages visited on our Internet content, etc.) Use profiles are generated from this data, using a pseudonym that does not allow conclusions to be drawn about the user and therefore cannot be used to identify a specific user. The information collected by the cookie concerning your use of this website (including your IP address) is transferred to a server in the United States of America and stored there. Google then removes the last three digits of the IP address, thus ensuring that the IP address can no longer be uniquely identified. Under no circumstances will Google associate your IP address with other information held by Google. Google complies with the data privacy provisions of the “EU-U.S. Privacy Shield” framework.

This procedure, known as “Google remarketing”, allows anonymous recognition by Google’s websites. Your browser is identified when advertising content is supplied and assigned to a particular target group. With the aid of this information, it is possible to show you advertisements that are more relevant and address your particular interests. Google uses this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity for the operators of the websites, and to provide additional services related to the use of the website and the Internet. Google may also transmit this information to third parties when required by law or when third parties process such information on behalf of Google.

Depending on your interests, a targeted provision of advertisements relevant to you is enabled when you visit the websites of other providers.

You may object at any time to the future collection and storage of your data by Google. Call up your display settings in Google under http://www.google.de/settings/ads and deactivate the display of interest-related advertisements by Google under “deactivation settings”. This will prevent Google from displaying targeted advertising for you. An “opt out” cookie is then placed that prevents future collection of your data when you visit this website. Please note that, if you delete all cookies from your computer, the deactivation cookie is deleted along with them, and must be stored again if needed.

You can find further information regarding the terms of Google’s privacy policy at http://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy.

In addition, as a general matter, you can prevent the placing of cookies by adjusting your browser settings accordingly.

### VII. Is personal information forwarded to third parties?

A forwarding on of your data to other companies, such as our co-operation or advertising partners, only takes place if your have expressly agreed to a transmission of your data and receipt of adverts from these companies within the framework of the respective campaign.

In certain cases, we are also required by law to disclose your personal information to third parties. This is for example the case when the suspicion of a criminal offence or a misuse of our websites occurs. We are then required to disclose your data to law enforcement authorities.

Outside of the cases described in this data protection declaration, your data is not forwarded on to third parties and, your information is solely stored in our databases / on our servers (or on the servers of third party providers).

### VIII. Legal bases

The legal bases for the processing of your data could be the following:

  * your consent to the use of data in accordance with Art. 6 (1) lit. a) GDPR;
  * the performance of our service obligations arising from contracts concluded with you in order to provide the services you request in accordance with Article 6 (1) lit. (b) GDPR;
  * our legitimate interest in accordance with Art. 6 (1) lit. f) GDPR, e. g.
  * our business interests in improving our services so that we can better understand your needs and expectations and thus improve the services we provide to you;
  * to prevent fraud and to ensure that our websites are used completely and without any fraudulent behaviour;
  * to ensure and guarantee the security of our services, making sure that our offer is technically secure and properly functioning;
  * to ensure and enforce our contractual requirements and claims.
  * Legal reasons in accordance with Art. 6 (1) lit. c) GDPR if collection, storage, transfer or other processing of data is prescribed by law or processing is necessary to fulfil our legal obligations.

### IX. Hyperlinks to other websites

In addition, our websites contain hyperlinks to websites offered by third parties When clicked, the hyperlinks redirect you from our website directly to the website of another provider. You can recognize this redirection process by the change of the URL in your web browser’s address bar. If you have been forwarded to the website of a cooperation or promotional partner, the use of your personal information will only be subject to the privacy policy of the relevant provider. We cannot take any responsibility for the privacy practices of third parties´ websites because we do have no control over their compliance with data protection regulations.

### X. Protection of minors

Persons under 18 years are excluded from our services and from providing any personal information without the consent of their parents or guardians. We do not request personal information from children and adolescents. We do not knowingly gather or collect such data and do not disclose it to third parties.

### XI. How we keep your information secure

When we collect information, we solely store your data on highly protected servers in Germany and the EU. Access to our IT infrastructure is strictly limited to authorised persons who are involved in the technical, commercial or editorial support.

In order to avoid loss or misuse of data stored by us, we have taken all necessary and extensive technical and organisational safety precautions, which are regularly checked and updated based on technological advancements in accordance to the GDPR.

However, we would like to inform you that because of the nature of the Internet, the provisions of data protection and data security measures described in this Privacy Policy may not be observed by any third parties or institutions beyond our control. Especially unencrypted data transmission – even when sent via e-mail – can be read by third parties. We have no technical influence on this. The user has the responsibility to protect the information he provides from misuse by encryption, selection of a secure password or other means.

We store personal information you submit to us only for as long as is necessary to fulfil the purposes for which such information was transmitted, or as required by law:

  * if you conclude contracts with us, we store and process your personal data for the duration of the contractual relationship and beyond for the fulfilment of post-contractual obligations and handling of issues as well as for the duration of statutory retention periods (maximum 10 years);
  * If you have consented to the promotional use of your e-mail address, we will store your e-mail address in our mailing database until you unsubscribe, requesting us to delete the data;
  * If you send us an enquiry, we process your personal data while we handle your request.

### XII. Rights of the “data subject” according to the rules of the GDPR:

According to the EU General Data Protection Regulation, you deserve the right to request access to your personal data (see Art. 15), as well as rectification (see Art. 16), erasure (see Art. 17) or at least restriction of processing (see Art. 18) of your personal data.

Furthermore, you have a right to data portability (see Art. 20) and, of course, the right to revoke any consent given to the processing of personal data at any time (see Art. 7) and to object to processing based on the balancing of legitimate interests (see Art. 21(4) GDPR). In addition, you have a right of appeal to the competent data protection supervisory authority.

____

Rechtsanwalt Stephan Krämer, LL.M.,   
Kinast & Partner Rechtsanwälte  
http://www.kinast-partner.de/

Ligatus GmbH  
Christophstraße 19,   
50670 Cologne  
Germany  
E-Mail: privacyquestions@outbrain.com

Version: September 2018 - We reserve the right to adapt this data protection declaration and will announce any changes in good time.

The Ligatus website uses cookies. You can learn more about these cookies by visiting our [Privacy Policy page](https://www.ligatus.com/en/privacy-policy). By continuing to access this website, you consent to our use of cookies.

OK
